Guide to the Edwin Hale Abbot Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- VOLUMES, 1836-1915; Series IV; 15' (55 boxes)
  - Railroads, Mines, and Businesses
    - Oversize
      - American McKenna Process Company
        - Dividend checks registers, 1902-1912 (Box 79, Folder 480-481)
        - Dividend receipt book, 1901-1907 (Box 79, Folder 482)
        - Journal, 1903-1914 (Box 80, Folder 483)
        - Ledger, 1903-1914 (Box 80, Folder 484)
        - Schedule of preferred dividend certificates, 1901-1915 (Box 81, Folder 485)
      - Chicago, Wisconsin and Minnesota Railroad Company
        - Stock certificates, 1886-1896 (Box 81, Folder 486)
        - Stock certificates, 1897-1898 (Box 82, Folder 487)
        - Stock certificates, 1897-1898 (Box 83, Folder 488)
        - Stock ledger, 1886-1902 (Box 83, Folder 489)
      - Colby, Abbot & Hoyt, Trustees
        - Voucher statement: Chicago & Great Western Railroad Company, undated (Box 84, Folder 490)
      - Comet Iron Mining Company
        - Stock certificates, 1890 (Box 84, Folder 491)
      - English McKenna Process Company
        - Cash book, 1903-1911 (Box 84, Folder 492)
        - Cash book and journal, 1903-1911 (Box 84, Folder 493)
        - Journal, 1903-1905 (Box 85, Folder 494)
        - Ledgers, 1903-1911 (Box 85, Folder 495-496)
        - Stock certificates, 1905-1910 (Box 86, Folder 497-498)
        - Stock certificates, 1905-1910 (Box 87, Folder 499)
      - Gogebic Electric Company
        - Stock certificates, 1891-1893 (Box 87, Folder 500)
      - Ironwood Electric Company
        - Stock certificates, 1891 (Box 87, Folder 501)
      - Minnesota, St. Croix and Wisconsin Railroad Company
        - Stock certificates, 1885-1888 (Box 87, Folder 502)
      - Palms Iron Mining Company
        - Stock certificates, 1890 (Box 87, Folder 503)
      - Penokee & Gogebic Consolidated Mines
        - Stock certificates, 1890-1894 (Box 87, Folder 504)
        - Stock certificates, 1890-1896 (Box 88, Folder 505)
      - Penokee & Gogebic Development Company
        - Stock certificates, 1884-1891 (Box 88, Folder 506-507)
      - Penokee Railroad Company
        - Stock certificates, 1887-1888 (Box 89, Folder 508-509)
      - Superior Iron Mining Company
        - Stock certificates, 1890 (Box 89, Folder 510)
      - Wisconsin and Minnesota Railroad Company
        - Stock certificates, 1885-1887 (Box 89, Folder 511)
      - Wisconsin Central Company
        - Cash book, 1890-1893 (Box 89, Folder 512)
      - Wisconsin Central Railroad Company
        - Land income notes, 1876 (Box 90, Folder 513)
        - Registered certificates, 1875 (Box 90, Folder 514)
        - Stock ledgers, 1871-1874, 1879 (Box 90, Folder 515-516)
        - Warrant certificates, 1875-1878 (Box 91, Folder 517)
      - [Various interests?]
        - Accounts and trial balances, 1862-1867 (Box 91, Folder 518)
        - Bills receivable, 1867 (Box 91, Folder 519)
  - Legal cases
    - Abbot, Edwin H., v. Sentinel Company et. al., 1882 (Box 92, Folder 520)
    - Farmers' Loan & Trust Company v. Northern Pacific Railroad Company et. al., 1894
      - pp. 1-1083 (Box 92, Folder 521-524)
      - pp. 1084-3408, indexes, miscellanea (Box 93, Folder 525-530)
      - Arguments before A. L. Cary (Box 94, Folder 531)
    - Stewart & Abbot, Trustees v. Wisconsin Central Company
      - 1875-1892 (Box 95, Folder 532-533)
      - 1896, 1898 (Box 96, Folder 534-538)
      - 1898-1899 (Box 97, Folder 539-540)
    - Town of Weyauwega (Wisconsin) v. Charles H. Ayling, 1876-1879 (Box 97, Folder 541)
    - Miscellaneous, 1897, 1904, undated (Box 97, Folder 542)
  - Personal records
    - Abbot, Edwin Hale
      - General
        - Account books, 1851-1862, 1875-1880 (Box 98, Folder 543-544)
        - Bank books, 1857, 1889-1890, 1895-1896. (Box 98, Folder 545-546)
        - Cash book, 1858-1880 (Box 98, Folder 547)
        - Cash books, 1861-1870 (Box 99, Folder 548-553)
        - Cash books, 1871, 1877-1887 (Box 100, Folder 554-557)
        - Diaries, 1853-1858, 1877, 1879 (Box 101, Folder 558-560)
        - Diary, 1881 (Box 102, Folder 561)
        - Ledger, 1861-1865 (Box 102, Folder 562)
        - Memorandum books, 1863, 1868, 1873-1885, 1896 (Box 102, Folder 563-564)
        - Notes receivable, 1874-1881, 1886-1887 (Box 102, Folder 565)
        - Miscellaneous volumes, 1871-1872, undated (Box 102, Folder 566)
      - Oversize
        - Cash book, 1871-1875 (Box 103, Folder 567)
        - Ledger, 1866-1875 (Box 103, Folder 568)
    - [Abbot, Edwin Hale?]
      - Notebook on English history, undated (Box 104, Folder 569)
    - Others
      - Abbot, Edward B.
        - Fowler's Practical Phrenology, by O.S. Fowler, with ms. phrenological analysis of Edward B. Abbot by L. N. Fowler, 1840, undated (Box 104, Folder 570)
      - Abbot, Edward Stanley
        - Cash book, undated (Box 104, Folder 571)
        - Civil War records, including estate accounts kept by E. H. Abbot, 1862-1866, undated (Box 104, Folder 572)
      - Abbot, Fanny Ellingwood (Larcom)
        - Journal kept for her son, E. H. Abbot, 1836 (Box 104, Folder 573)
      - Abbot, Frederick
        - Bank book kept as Charles L. Colby's trustee, 1894-1896 (Box 104, Folder 574)
      - Abbot, Henry Larcom
        - Account book kept by E. H. Abbot, 1854-1865 (Box 104, Folder 575)
      - Abbot, Martha Trask (Steele)
        - Cash book kept by E. H. Abbot, 1875-1878 (Box 104, Folder 576)
      - Abbot, Mary (Carter)
        - Account book re: sewing, 1856-1859 (Box 105, Folder 577)
        - Diaries, 1856-1859 (Box 105, Folder 578)
      - Abbot, Philip Stanley
        - Account books, 1887, 1895 (Box 105, Folder 579)
        - Lists of books and other belongings, undated (Box 105, Folder 580)
        - Memorandum book, 1884 (Box 105, Folder 580)
      - Colby, Charles L., estate
        - Cash book and journal, 1896-1899 (Box 105, Folder 581)
        - Correspondence and papers, 1895-1909, undated (Box 106, Folder 582-584)
        - Ledger, 1896-1899 (Box 106, Folder 585)
        - Schedule of assets, [1898?] (Box 106, Folder 586)
        - Transcripts of statements, 1896-1900 (Box 107, Folder 587)
        - Trustees' cash book journal and ledger, 1899-1909 (Box 107, Folder 588)
      - Larcom, Henry, estate
        - Account book, 1862-1865 (Box 107, Folder 589)
      - Steele, Abby A.
        - Ledger, 1884-1886 (Box 107, Folder 590)
      - [Steele & Hayes?]
        - Notes and bills journal, 1860-1866 (Box 107, Folder 591)
      - Unidentified
        - "Communications with spirit world", 1854-1856 (Box 107, Folder 592)
        - Sermons, undated (Box 107, Folder 593)
- MAPS, BLUEPRINTS, AND DRAWINGS, 1828-1929, 1836-1915; Series V; 3' (8 boxes)
  This series contains material arranged alphabetically by company, geographic or personal name within three subseries: Railroads, Mines, and Businesses, Regions, and Personal Property and Miscellanea.
  - Railroads, Mines, and Businesses
    - American McKenna Process Company, New Jersey, 1902 (Box 108, Folder 594)
    - American Steel Barge Company, Wisconsin: proposed steamer for carrying railroad cars, 1894, undated (Box 108, Folder 595)
    - Ashland Iron Mining Company, Wisconsin, 1888-1896, undated (Box 108, Folder 596-598)
    - Aurora Iron Mining Company, Michigan, 1890-1891 (Box 108, Folder 599)
    - Bessemer Mine, Michigan, 1885 (Box 108, Folder 600)
    - Chicago & Great Western Railroad Company, and others: Grand Central Passenger Station and yard, Chicago
      - 1874, 1885-1888 (Box 108, Folder 601-602)
      - 1889, undated (Box 109, Folder 603-605)
    - Chicago and Western Indiana Railroad, and Belt Railway of Chicago, undated (Box 109, Folder 606)
    - Colby Mine and Tilden Mine, Michigan, undated (Box 109, Folder 607)
    - Comet Mining Company, Michigan, 1891 (Box 109, Folder 608)
    - English McKenna Process Company, Poulton cum Seacombe, Chester, England, 1899-1903, undated (Box 109, Folder 609-610)
    - Even Wear Rail Joint, 1929 (Box 109, Folder 611)
    - Flint & Pere Marquette Railroad, Wisconsin and Michigan, undated (Box 110, Folder 612)
    - Lake Washington Belt Line Company, Washington, 1890, undated (Box 110, Folder 613)
    - Milwaukee & Lake Winnebago Railroad Company, and others: Manitowoc, Wisconsin, terminal yard and harbor
      - 1895-1898, undated (Box 110, Folder 614-618)
      - undated (Box 111, Folder 619)
    - Milwaukee Line [Milwaukee & Lake Winnebago Railroad Company?], 1890 (Box 111, Folder 620)
    - Palms Iron Mining Company, Michigan, 1891 (Box 111, Folder 621)
    - Penokee & Gogebic Development Company, Wisconsin and Michigan, 1890 (Box 111, Folder 622)
    - Superior Mining Company, Wisconsin, 1891 (Box 111, Folder 623)
    - Wisconsin Central Company and Wisconsin Central Railroad Company
      - General and miscellaneous, 1875, 1882-1898, undated (Box 111, Folder 624-627)
      - Ashland-Wheeling, 1882-1898, n.d (Box 112, Folder 628-631)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified
      - Railroad maps, undated (Box 112, Folder 632)
      - Railroad stations and office buildings, undated (Box 112, Folder 633)
      - Railroad stations and office buildings, undated (Box 113, Folder 634)
  - Regions
    - Michigan, 1890, undated (Box 113, Folder 635)
    - Minnesota: St. Paul, 1886, 1891, undated (Box 113, Folder 636)
    - Washington, 1888-1896, undated (Box 113, Folder 637)
    - West Virginia, 1864 (Box 113, Folder 638)
    - Wisconsin
      - General and miscellaneous, 1866, 1875, 1881-1888 (Box 113, Folder 639)
      - General and miscellaneous, 1889-1894, 1906, undated (Box 114, Folder 640)
      - Abbotsford, 1900, 1902, undated (Box 114, Folder 641)
      - Milwaukee, 1883-1892, undated (Box 114, Folder 642)
    - Wisconsin and Michigan, 1883, 1886, undated (Box 114, Folder 643)
  - Personal Property and Miscellanea
    - Civil War maps of South, with letter from Gen. Samuel Cooper to the Confederate War Department, 1862 (Box 114, Folder 644)
    - Property
      - Maine (Steele family), 1851-1888, undated (Box 114, Folder 645)
      - Massachusetts, 1864-1911, undated (Box 114, Folder 646)
      - Unidentified, 1828, 1836, 1868, undated (Box 114, Folder 647)
- FINANCIAL AND LEGAL PAPERS, 1833-1928; Series VI; 2.5' (6 boxes)
  This series contains material arranged alphabetically by company or personal name within two subseries: Railroads, Mines, and Businesses and Personal Records.
  - Railroads, Mines, and Businesses
    - American McKenna Process Company, 1928 (Box 115, Folder 648)
    - Ashland Iron Mining Company, 1871-1887, undated (Box 115, Folder 649)
    - Aurora Iron Mining Company, 1889 (Box 115, Folder 650)
    - Central Car Company, 1899 (Box 115, Folder 651)
    - Chicago & Great Western Railroad Company, 1873, 1885-1890, undated (Box 115, Folder 652-654)
    - Chicago and Northern Pacific Railroad Company, 1892-1893 (Box 115, Folder 655-656)
    - Chicago South Branch Dock Company, 1876 (Box 116, Folder 657)
    - Chicago, Wisconsin and Minnesota Railroad Company, 1885-1886, undated (Box 116, Folder 658)
    - Consolidated Colby Mines, 1887 (Box 116, Folder 659)
    - Everett land Company, Washington, 1891-1900 (Box 116, Folder 660-661)
    - Kanawha [Canal?] Coal Mining and Oil Manufacturing Company, West Virginia, 1865 (Box 116, Folder 662)
    - Lake Washington Belt Line Company
      - 1890-1892 (Box 116, Folder 663-664)
      - 1893-1901, undated (Box 117, Folder 665-669)
    - Manitowoc and Western Railroad Company, 1895-1896 (Box 120, Folder 670)
    - Manitowoc Land Improvement Company, 1895-1900 (Box 118, Folder 671)
    - Milwaukee & Lake Winnebago Railroad Company, 1882, 1884, 1895-1896, undated (Box 118, Folder 672-673)
    - Minneapolis, Saint Paul and Sail t Ste. Marie Railroad Company, 1881 (Box 118, Folder 674)
    - Minnesota, St. Croix and Wisconsin Railroad Company, 1884, 1886, undated (Box 118, Folder 675)
    - Monte Cristo Mining Company, 1892 (Box 118, Folder 676)
    - Penokee Railroad Company, 1886, undated (Box 118, Folder 677)
    - Superior Lumber Company, 1883 (Box 118, Folder 678)
    - Western States Construction Company, 1884-1885 (Box 119, Folder 679-680)
    - Wilkeson Coal & Coke Company, 1894-1896 (Box 119, Folder 681)
    - Wisconsin and Minnesota Railroad Company, 1880, 1884, 1897, undated (Box 119, Folder 682)
    - Wisconsin Central Company and Wisconsin Central Railroad Company, 1874-1876, 1885-1896, undated (Box 119, Folder 683)
    - Various companies: stock and bond certificates, 1869-1882, undated (Box 119, Folder 684)
    - Unidentified companies, 1862-1875, 1884, 1894-1906, undated (Box 120, Folder 685-686)
  - Personal records
    - Abbot, Edwin Hale
      - Harvard College bills, 1860-1861 (Box 120, Folder 687)
      - Insurance certificates and family agreement, 1857, 1867-1870 (Box 120, Folder 688)
      - Papers concerning Massachusetts property, 1863, 1903-1906, undated (Box 120, Folder 689)
    - Steele family
      - Papers concerning Maine property, and miscellanea, 1833-1868, 1883, undated (Box 120, Folder 690)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1895-1914, 1845-1914; Series VII; 4.5' (7 boxes)
  This series contains material arranged alphabetically by company or personal name within two subseries: Railroads and Businesses and Family and Miscellanea.
  - Railroads and Businesses
    - [Chicago & Great Western Railroad Company?]: construction of Grand Central Passenger Station, Chicago, 1888-1890 (Box 121, Folder 691-692)
    - English McKenna Process Company
      - Album, 1903-1904 (Box 122, Folder 693)
      - Album, 1904-1907 (Box 123, Folder 694)
      - Loose photographs, 1898, undated (Box 123, Folder 695)
    - Milwaukee & Lake Winnebago Railroad Company: construction of Manitowoc, Wisconsin, terminal yard and harbor, 1896-1897, undated (Box 124, Folder 696-700)
    - Wisconsin Central Railroad Company
      - Iron ore yard at Ironwood, Michigan, 1894 (Box 125, Folder 701)
      - Views of Wisconsin along the line, undated (Box 125, Folder 702-703)
  - Family and Miscellanea
    - Guide to numbered photographs, with genealogical notes, undated (Box 125, Folder 704)
    - Numbered photographs
      - 1 - 64, undated (Box 125, Folder 705-708)
      - 65-112, undated (Box 126, Folder 709-711)
      - 01-024, Circa 1854-1906 (Box 126, Folder 712-714)
    - Abbot, Edward Stanley, undated (Box 126, Folder 715)
    - Abbot, Edwin Hale, 1855, undated (Box 126, Folder 716)
    - Abbot, Mary (Carter), undated (Box 126, Folder 717)
    - Abbot, Philip Stanley, 1868-1877, undated (Box 126, Folder 718)
    - Abbot, Sarah Otis (Ernst): albums and loose photographs, 1898-1899, undated (Box 126, Folder 719)
    - Other family members, Circa 1854-1906 (Box 127, Folder 720)
    - Others (non-family), Circa 1845-1914 (Box 127, Folder 721-722)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified
      - People, undated (Box 127, Folder 723-726)
      - Places, undated (Box 127, Folder 727)
- PHILLIPS BROOKS HOUSE, 1890-1910; Series VIII; 1' (3 boxes)
  - 1890 - 1893 (Box 128, Folder 728-738)
  - 1894 - 1900 January 15 (Box 129, Folder 739-751)
  - 1900 January 15 - 1901, 1910, undated (Box 130, Folder 752-761)
- MEMORABILIA AND PERSONAL PAPERS, 1861-1894; Series IX; 1' (3 boxes)
  This series contains material arranged according to type of material.
  - Greeting cards, undated (Box 131, Folder 762)
  - Literary works (Box 131, Folder 763-763d)
    - "Ne-Con-Dis", 1894 (Box 131, Folder 763-763d)
    - "Jospeh Hale Abbot" by William F. Abbot, undated (Box 131, Folder 763-763d)
  - Printed memorabilia, 1861-1878 (Box 131, Folder 764)
  - Railroad pass and ticket catalogs, undated (Box 131, Folder 765)
  - Railroad passes and tickets, undated (Box 132, Folder 765)
  - Railroad passes and tickets, undated (Box 133, Folder 765)
- OVERSIZE, 1808-1931; Series X; 2' (3 boxes)
  This series contains materials arranged alphabetically within two subseries: Maps, Blueprints, and Drawings and Financial and Legal Papers. The latter subseries contains the sub-subseries Railroads, Mines, and Businesses and Personal Records.
  - Maps, Blueprints, and Drawings
    - Chicago and Northwestern Railway: Oshkosh, Wisconsin, yard, 1909 (Box 134, Folder 766)
    - Colby and Abbot Building, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, with photograph and financial and legal papers, 1909, 1920, undated (Box 134, Folder 767)
    - Wisconsin Central Depot, Chicago, undated (Box 134, Folder 768)
    - Wisconsin: Jones Island resurvey, 1914 (Box 134, Folder 769)
    - Wisconsin and Michigan: Penokee & Gogebic Iron Range, 1893 (Box 134, Folder 770)
  - Financial and Legal Papers
    - Railroads, Mines, and Businesses
      - English McKenna Process Company, 1902-1903 (Box 135, Folder 771)
      - Wisconsin Central Company, 1887-1897 (Box 135, Folder 772)
      - Wisconsin Central Railroad Company, 1872-1889, undated (Box 135, Folder 773)
      - Various companies, 1870-1896 (Box 135, Folder 774)
    - Personal records
      - Colby, Charles L., and Gardner Colby, with engraving, 1882, 1900, undated (Box 136, Folder 775)
      - Insurance policies, 1852-1896 (Box 136, Folder 776)
      - Passports, 1869-1889 (Box 136, Folder 777)
      - Property
        - Illinois, 1872-1874 (Box 136, Folder 778)
        - Maine (Steele family), 1808-1886, undated (Box 136, Folder 779)
        - Massachusetts, 1843-1906, undated (Box 136, Folder 780)
        - Michigan, 1877, 1887 (Box 136, Folder 781)
        - Minnesota, 1877 (Box 136, Folder 781)
        - New York, 1874-1889 (Box 136, Folder 782)
        - Ohio, 1872 (Box 136, Folder 782)
        - Wisconsin, 1840-1905 (Box 136, Folder 783)
        - Miscellaneous, 1897 (Box 136, Folder 784)
      - Shipping papers, 1864-1872 (Box 136, Folder 785)
      - Miscellaneous accounts, 1834-1931, undated (Box 136, Folder 786)
- Additional Material, Accession 1999-M-050
  - Drawings and blueprints [miscellaneous, including railroads, steel processors, ferries, and personal properties] (Box 1)
  - Drawings and blueprints [miscellaneous, including railroads, steel processors, ferries, and personal properties] (Box 2)
  - Drawings and blueprints [miscellaneous, including railroads, steel processors, ferries, and personal properties] (Box 3)
  - Drawings and blueprints [miscellaneous, including railroads, steel processors, ferries, and personal properties] (Box 4)
  - Drawings and blueprints [miscellaneous, including railroads, steel processors, ferries, and personal properties] (Box 5)
  - Drawings and blueprints [miscellaneous, including railroads, steel processors, ferries, and personal properties] (Box 6)